Guide to the Hermann Broch Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1913-88; Series II; 16; (39 boxes)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Articles and Essays
      - "Politik: Ein Kondensat": draft fragments (Box 54, Folder 1248-54)
      - "Die positivistische Philosophie der Mathematik": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1255)
      - "The Problem": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1256)
      - "Proposal for a Law to Protect Human Dignity"
        "Forderung nach einem Gesetz zum Schutz der Menschenwürde"
        - Draft A, typescript, carbons, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1257)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon (Box 54, Folder 1258)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon (Box 54, Folder 1259)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1260)
        - Draft, typescript and carbon (Box 54, Folder 1261)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1262)
      - "Pros und Cons zu Prof. Gurians Einwänden gegen Weltstaat-Projekte": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1947 Mar (Box 54, Folder 1263)
      - "Publius Virgilius Maro stammte von bescheidenen Eltern..."
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1264)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected (English), n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1265)
      - Das "Recht an sich"...: draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1266)
      - "Rede über Viertel"
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1267)
        - Plan: printed version, 1947 (Box 54, Folder 1268)
      - "Der Regisseur": printed version, c. 1934 (Box 55, Folder 1269)
      - "Religiöse Dichtung?"
        - Draft, bound, typescript, corrected [bound together with "Einheit wissenschaftlicher und dichterischer Erkenntnis,"
          See: Box 49, folder 1097
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1270)
      - "Die Rettung": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1271)
      - "Rundfunk": draft, typescript, 1950 (Box 55, Folder 1272)
      - "Der russische Totalitärstaat": draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1273)
      - Schiffrin, Jacques (obituary): drafts, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1274)
      - "Der Schriftsteller Franz Blei," Prager Presse: printed version, 1921 Apr 20 (Box 55, Folder 1275)
      - Schweiger, Clotilde (obituary): draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1276)
      - "Eine Selbstbiographie als Arbeitsprogram"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1277)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected and carbon (English) (Box 55, Folder 1278)
      - "Die sogenannten philosophischen Grundfragen einer empirischen Wissenschaft"
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1279)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon (Box 55, Folder 1280)
      - "Star of the Unborn: A Film Exposé of Franz Werfel's Last Novel"
        - Draft, typescript, carbon (German), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1281)
        - Draft, typescript, mimeograph, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1282)
      - "Stellung des mathematischen Bereiches im System der Bereiche": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1283)
      - "Strategischer Imperialismus"
        - Research notes, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1284)
        - Preliminary study, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1285)
        - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1286)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbons, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1287)
        - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1288)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbons, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1289)
        - Draft C, typescript, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1290)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1291)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1292)
      - "Das System als Weltbewältigung"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1293)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1294)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1295)
      - "Technische Bemerkungen zum Stil im 'Tod des Vergil,'" Moderner Buch-Club: printed version, 1960 May (Box 55, Folder 1296)
      - "Der Theaterkritiker Polgar"
        - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1297)
        - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1298)
      - "Theodor Sabest, Wirt und Fleischer," Literarische Revue: printed version (Box 56, Folder 1299)
      - "Theorie der Geschichtsschreibung und der Geschichtsphilosophie": draft, holograph (Box 56, Folder 1300)
      - "Theory of Mass Aberration in Outline"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1301)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1302)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1303)
      - "Der Tod des Vergil: Betrachtungen Hermann Brochs zum Stil seines Werkes," Hamburger Akademische Rundschau: printed version, 1948 Mar (Box 56, Folder 1304)
      - "Totale Humanität, unbequem aber möglich und notwendig": draft, typescript (Box 56, Folder 1305)
      - "Trotzdem: Humane Politik. Verwirklichung einer Utopie"
        - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1306)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1307)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1308)
        - Corrections, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1309)
        - Die neue Rundschau: printed version (Box 56, Folder 1310)
      - "The Twentythird or Thirtythird Amendment": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 56, Folder 1311)
      - "Über Marx"
        - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1312)
        - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1313)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1314)
      - "Über Modelle"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1315)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1316)
        - "Skizze einer erkenntniskritischen Werttheorie": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1317)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1318)
      - "Über syntaktische und kognitive Einheiten"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1319)
        - Draft, typescript, carbons, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1320)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1321)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1322)
      - "Das Unmittelbare": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1323)
      - "Urbis humanum: Ein Aufruf zu einer Weltdemokratie"
        - Research material, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1324)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1325)
        - Printed version, photocopy (English), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1326)
      - "Victorious Defeat" by Fanny Colby: outline by Hermann Broch for a novel, draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1327)
      - "Vorschlag zur Gründung eines Forschungsinstitutes für politische Psychologie und zum Studium von Massenwahnerscheinungen"
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1328)
        - Draft, typescript, carbons, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1329)
      - "Vorschläge für den 'Council for Democracy'": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1330)
      - "Wasserkräfte und Abfallenergien im Wiener Ueberlandnetz": draft, typescript (Box 57, Folder 1331)
      - "Das Weltbild des Romans"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1332)
        - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1333)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1334)
      - "Werttheoretische Bemerkungen zur Psychoanalyse"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1335)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1336)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1337)
      - Werttheorie, Unidentified essay on: draft, typescript (Box 57, Folder 1338)
      - "Werttheorie: Geist der Philosophie": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1339)
      - Will, Unidentified essay on: draft, typescript and carbon (Box 57, Folder 1340)
      - "Zerfall der Werte"
        See also: Box 34, folder 839
        - Draft A, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1341)
        - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1342)
        - Printed version, negative photocopy, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1343)
        - Printed version, positive photocopy, edited for separate publication, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1344)
        - Galley proofs, corrected (English), n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1345)
      - "Zolas Vorurteil"
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1346)
        - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1347)
      - "Zum Begriff der Geisteswissenschaften"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1348)
        - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1349)
        - Draft B, typescript, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1350)
        - Summa: printed version, photocopy, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1351)
      - "Zur Diktatur der Humanität innerhalb einer totalen Demokratie"
        - Draft, typescript and carbons (Box 57, Folder 1352)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon (English), n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1353)
      - "Zur Erkenntnis dieser Zeit"
        - Draft A, typescript, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1354)
        - Draft B, typescript and carbon (Box 57, Folder 1355)
        - Draft C, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1356)
        - Draft fragments, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1357)
      - "Zur Geschichte der Philosophie": draft, holograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1358)
      - "Zur Philosophie der Werte und der Geistigkeit": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 57, Folder 1359)
    - Book Reviews
      - List, 1966 Jul 13 (Box 58, Folder 1360)
      - Adler, H. G., Theresienstadt
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, 1949 May (Box 58, Folder 1361)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected (English), 1949 May (Box 58, Folder 1362)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon (English), 1949 May (Box 58, Folder 1363)
      - Adler, Max, Marx als Denker and Engels als Denker
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1921 (Box 58, Folder 1364)
        - Offprint, 1921 (Box 58, Folder 1365)
      - Bartsch, Rudolf Hans, Der junge Dichter: draft, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1366)
      - Baudelaire, Charles, Intime Tagebücher, Zeichnungen und Bildnisse: draft, typescript, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1367)
      - Baumgarten, Franz Ferdinand, Das Werk Conrad Ferdinand Meyers: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1368)
      - Beardsley, Aubrey, Venus und Tannhäuser: draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1369)
      - Blei, Franz, Formen der Liebe: draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1930 (Box 58, Folder 1370)
      - Block, Paul, Der verwandelte Bürger
        - Critique 1, draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1371)
        - Critique 2, draft, typescript, carbon, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1372)
      - Braun-Vogelstein, Julie, Kuenstlerische Form des Abendlandes: draft, typescript, carbon (Box 58, Folder 1373)
      - Butler, Charles E., Follow Me Ever
        - First draft, typescript, corrected, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 1374)
        - Final draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 1375)
        - Draft fragments, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 1376)
      - Dörmann, Felix, Der platonische Wüstling: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1377)
      - Edschmid, K., Stehe von Lichtern gestreichelt: draft, typescript, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1378)
      - Flesch, Hans
        Balthasar Tipho
        - Critique 1, draft, typescript, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1379)
        - Critique 2, draft, typescript, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1380)
        - Gegenspiel: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1381)
      - Handl, Willi, Die Flamme
        - Critique 1, draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1382)
        - Critique 2, draft, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1383)
      - Heller, Frank, Des Kaisers alte Kleider: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1384)
      - Hirschfeld, L., Wo sind die Zeiten?: draft, typescript, carbon, 1921 (Box 58, Folder 1385)
      - Jammes, Francis, Klara: draft, typescript, carbon, 1921 (Box 58, Folder 1386)
      - Kaiser, Ernst, Die Geschichte eines Mordes: draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1387)
      - Kisch, Egon Erwin, Abenteuer in Prag: draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1388)
      - Leppin, Paul, Daniel Jesus
        - Critique 1, draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1389)
        - Critique 2, draft, typescript, carbon, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1390)
      - Meister, Hermann, Die Freunde: draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1391)
      - Metternich, Pauline, Geschehenes, Gesehenes, Erlebtes: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1392)
      - Michaelis, Karin, Don Juan im Tode: draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1921 (Box 58, Folder 1393)
      - Mulford, Prentice, Das Ende des Unfuges: draft, typescript, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1394)
      - Nexö, Martin Andersen, Die Familie Frank: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1395)
      - Otten, Karl, Lona: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1396)
      - Perutz, Leo, Der Marques de Bolibar
        - Critique 1, draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1397)
        - Critique 2, draft, typescript and carbon, corrected, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1398)
      - Petzold, Alfons, Das rauhe Leben: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1399)
      - Pick, Robert, The Terhoven File: draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1944 (Box 58, Folder 1400)
      - Polgar, Alfred, Kleine Zeit: draft, typescript, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1401)
      - Reiwald, Paul, Vom Geist der Massen: draft, typescript, corrected and carbon, 1946 (Box 58, Folder 1402)
      - Richter, Werner, Frankreich--von Gambetta zu Clemenceau: offprint, 1948 Jan (Box 58, Folder 1403)
      - Sack, Gustav, Der Namenlose: draft, typescript, carbon, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1404)
      - Salus, Hugo, Das neue Buch: draft, typescript, 1919 (Box 58, Folder 1405)
      - Sartre, Jean-Paul, L'être et le néant: draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1406)
      - Schäfer, Wilhelm, Drei Briefe: draft, typescript, carbon, 1921 (Box 58, Folder 1407)
      - Scheyer, Moriz, Europäer und Exoten: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1408)
      - Sommer, Ernst, Der Aufruhr: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1409)
      - Spaier, Albert, La pensée et la quantité
        - Critique 1, draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1927 (Box 58, Folder 1410)
        - Critique 2, draft, typescript, carbon, 1927 (Box 58, Folder 1411)
      - Srámek, Frána, Der silberne Wind: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1412)
      - Stein, Lorenz von, Geschichte der sozialen Bewegungen: draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1921 (Box 58, Folder 1413)
      - Stobl, Karl Hans, Gespenster im Sumpf: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1414)
      - Thiess, Heinz, Prometheus
        - Critique 1, draft, typescript, carbon, 1921 (Box 58, Folder 1415)
        - Critique 2, draft, typescript, carbon, 1921 (Box 58, Folder 1416)
      - Torberg, Friedrich, Hier bin ich, Mein Vater: draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1948 (Box 58, Folder 1417)
      - Weiss, Ernst, Stern der Dämonen: draft, typescript, carbon, 1921 (Box 58, Folder 1418)
      - Weltsch, Felix, Gnade und Freiheit: draft, typescript, carbon, 1920 (Box 58, Folder 1419)
    - Short Stories
      - "Ein Abend Angst," Berliner Börsen-Courier: printed version, 1933 Aug 6 (Box 58, Folder 1420)
      - "Die Heimkehr"
        - Die neue Rundschau: offprint, 1933 Dec (Box 58, Folder 1421)
        - Sinn und Form: offprint, 1949 (Box 58, Folder 1422)
      - "Eine leichte Enttäuschung," Die neue Rundschau: offprint, 1933 Apr (Box 58, Folder 1423)
      - "Der Meeresspiegel"
        - Draft A, bound, typescript (Box 58, Folder 1424)
        - Draft A, bound, typescript, carbon (Box 58, Folder 1425)
        - Draft B, bound, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 58, Folder 1426)
        - Printed version, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1427)
      - "Noch immer bebt mir das Herz vor Fernweh...": draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1428)
      - "Oh Vöglein geschwindes...": draft, typescript (Box 58, Folder 1429)
      - "Vorüberziehende Wolke"
        See also: Box 34, folder 861
        - Frankfurter Zeitung: printed version, 1933 Apr 21 (Box 58, Folder 1430)
        - "A Passing Cloud," The Modern Scot: printed version (translation by Willa Muir), 1934 Jan (Box 58, Folder 1431)
      - "Wer darf wagen..."
        - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1432)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1433)
- Writings of Others, 1901-89; Series III; 1; (2 boxes)
  Series III, Writings of Others (Boxes 59-60), is organized into two subseries: Writings about Broch and General. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically according to author and there- under by title. In general, this material dates from Broch's lifetime or was written by his close friends. More recent material of this sort is kept in a vertical file in the German Literature Collection.
  - WRITINGS ABOUT BROCH
    - Arendt, Hannah
      "Hermann Broch und der moderne Roman"
      - Draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 1434)
      - Printed version, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 1435)
      - "No Longer and Not Yet": printed version, 1946 Sep 14 (Box 59, Folder 1436)
    - Bunzel, Joseph H., "Hermann Broch as a Teacher": draft, typescript, corrected and printed version, 1952 (Box 59, Folder 1437)
    - Durzak, Manfred, "Epilog des Wertzerfalls. Zu Hermann Broch": printed version, 1966 May (Box 59, Folder 1438)
    - Frisé, Adolf, "Hermann Broch oder Verwirrung und Wirklichkeit des Daseins": typescript, photocopy, 1952 Oct (Box 59, Folder 1439)
    - Hassold, Ernest C.
      - "Hermann Broch on James Joyce": draft, typescript, corrected, 1962 (Box 59, Folder 1440)
      - "Virgil's Last 24 Hours as a Verbal Symphony"
        - Draft, mimeograph, ca. 1945 (Box 59, Folder 1441)
        - Printed version, 1945 Aug 12 (Box 59, Folder 1442)
    - Huxley, Aldous, The Death of Virgil
      - Draft A, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1443)
      - Draft B, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1444)
    - Jaffé, Aniela, "Hermann Broch: Der Tod des Vergil: Ein Beitrag zum Problem der Individuation": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 59, Folder 1445)
    - Kahler, Alice Loewy ("Lili")
      - Untitled poem for Hermann Broch's birthday: draft, typescript, photocopy, 1947 Nov 1 (Box 59, Folder 1446)
      - "Zum 25. Todestag von Hermann Broch": draft, typescript, corrected, 1976 (Box 59, Folder 1446)
    - Kahler, Antoinette ("Mama"), poems for Hermann Broch: holograph and typescript, 1941-49, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1447)
    - Kahler, Erich
      "Address Delivered on the Occasion of a Memorial for Hermann Broch at the Bollingen Foundation, November 1, 1951"
      - Draft A, holograph, corrected, 1951 (Box 59, Folder 1448)
      - Draft B, typescript, corrected, 1951 (Box 59, Folder 1449)
      - Draft C, typescript, mimeograph, 1951 (Box 59, Folder 1450)
      - Analysis of Der Tod des Vergil: draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1958 Apr (Box 59, Folder 1451)
      - Birthday poems for Hermann Broch ("Höhe des Lebens" and untitled), drafts, typescript and carbon, 1945-46 (Box 59, Folder 1452)
      - "The Epochal Innovations in Hermann Broch's Narrative"
        - Draft A, typescript, corrected (in German), 1968 (Box 59, Folder 1453)
        - Draft B, typescript, corrected, photocopy (in German), 1968 (Box 59, Folder 1454)
        - English translation, draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 1455)
      - Fragment of a lecture on Hermann Broch: draft, holograph, photocopy, 1950s (Box 59, Folder 1456)
      - "Die Geburt des Vergil": draft, holograph and photocopy and typescript, 1944 Jul 5 (Box 59, Folder 1457)
      - Lecture on Hermann Broch
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1950s (Box 59, Folder 1458)
        - Draft, typescript, carbon, 1959 (Box 59, Folder 1459)
      - Radio speech on Hermann Broch: draft holograph, corrected, 1964 (Box 59, Folder 1460)
    - Koch, Thilo, " Der Tod des Vergil: Einführung in eine Dichtung von Hermann Broch": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1949 Nov (Box 59, Folder 1461)
    - Kress, Frank
      - "Kritische Ausgabe des Vorwortes und des I. Kapitels der Drei Original- fassungen von Hermann Brochs Bergroman des 1953 gedruckten Textes" (dissertation): typescript, carbon, 1966 (Box 59, Folder 1462)
      - "Inhaltsverzeichnis der Bergroman typescript and carbon and photocopy, 1966 Jun (Box 59, Folder 1463)
    - Menck, Clara, "Hermann Broch: Der Tod des Vergil ": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1949 Sep (Box 59, Folder 1464)
    - Plunguian, [Gina ?], "Apology to Hermann Broch": typescript, with ink sketch of Broch, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1465)
    - Schönwiese, Ernst, "Die 'grossen alten Männer' der österreichischen Literatur": draft, mimeograph, 1968 Jun 23 (Box 59, Folder 1466)
    - Steinberg, Heinz, radio broadcast on Hermann Broch: typescript, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1467)
    - Taucher, Franz
      - Discussion of Der Tod des Vergil: draft, typescript, carbon, ca. 1946 (Box 60, Folder 1468)
      - "Vermächtnis an Hermann Broch" (poem): holograph, 1938 Jun 26 (Box 60, Folder 1469)
    - Thiess, Frank, excerpt from "Der deutsche Roman als Spiegel unserer Zeit": draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1470)
    - Türk, Rudolf, "Auf den Spuren von Hermann Broch": typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1471)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr
      - "The Promise" (poem): draft, typescript, 1947 Nov 1 (Box 60, Folder 1472)
      - "Some Remarks on Translation": draft, typescript, carbon, 1946 Nov (Box 60, Folder 1473)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr and Urzidil, Johannes, interview on Hermann Broch: typescript, mimeograph (Box 60, Folder 1474)
    - Waldinger, Ernst, poems for Hermann Broch: typescript, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1475)
    - Weigand, Hermann John
      - "Hermann Broch, In Memoriam": draft, typescript, carbon, corrected, 1951 Nov q (Box 60, Folder 1476)
      - "Hermann Broch's Die Schuldlosen: An Approach": draft, typescript, carbon, 1952 Jul 25 (Box 60, Folder 1477)
      - "Program Notes to Broch's Death of Vergil (sic)": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1478-79)
    - Wolff, Kurt H., "Hermann Broch Grande Memoria" (poem): typescript, 1951 (Box 60, Folder 1480)
    - Zweig, Stephan, " The Death of Virgil ": draft, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1481)
  - GENERAL
    - Brecht, Bertolt, "An die Nachgeborenen" (poem): typescript, carbon (Box 60, Folder 1482)
    - Bunzel, Joseph H., "Baroque Created America": draft, typescript, carbon, 1941 (Box 60, Folder 1483)
    - Cantril, Hadley, "Toward a Scientific Morality": offprint, 1949 (Box 60, Folder 1484)
    - Carnap, Rudolf and Reichenbach, Hans (ed.), Erkenntnis zugleich Annalen der Philosophie, Band I, Heft 1, ca. 1930 (Box 60, Folder 1485)
    - Federn, Paul
      See also: Oversize, Box 74, folder 1803
      - "A Dream under General Anesthesia": offprint, 1944 Jul (Box 60, Folder 1486)
      - "Principles of Psychotherapy in Latent Schizophrenia": offprint, 1947 Apr (Box 60, Folder 1487)
      - "The Psychiatric Social Worker's Concern with Shock Treatment": offprint, 1945 (Box 60, Folder 1488)
      - "Psychoanalytische Auffassung der intellektuellen Hemmung, 1930 (Box 60, Folder 1489)
      - "Sándor Ferenczi": offprint, 1933 (Box 60, Folder 1490)
      - "Über die Wirkung sexueller Kräfte in der Seele": offprint, 1931 (Box 60, Folder 1491)
      - "Über zwei typische Traumsensationen": offprint, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1492)